Hi, this is John Stewart, and this is how to raise the tent when setting up your tent.
Once you've got your poles inserted into the tent, you can then raise up your tent.
Once you've got the poles crisscrossed at the center, most of the time, they're tied together to where they're standing and you don't have to hold them any longer, you can then go into raising the tent.
The tent's going to have two things to put it through, you can either have the poles that have sleeves that Velcro over the pole, or you'll have clips.
Both of them are very fast and efficient to set up.
The clips seem to be a little bit sturdier.
You just go along the pole and clip them one by one until you get them all clipped.
Once you've got them clipped, the tent should be stood upright.
And then you can go into staking out your tent.
One thing to remember is that setting up a tent, you can do this with one person.
Yes, it can get frustrating, but just take your time, and it'll go up nice and smoothly.
And if you do have that friend, grab him and they can help you out.
And this is how to raise the tent.